# **ANTHONY RODEZ**

720.418.9032 Louisville, CO Rodez.A@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Principal Engineer with deep and broad experience in small, medium, and large Fortune 500 companies, working directly with executives, leading teams, and projects across numerous business verticals. Solid track record of gathering requirements and translating them into scalable solutions with leading-edge technologies. Major strengths include interpersonal, quantitative, and problem solving skills. Areas of focus:

- AWS Cloud / Data Engineering / Python
- Analytics / AI-ML / Data Science

- Modern Data Architecture / Big Data / Agile
- BI-DW / DevOps / Software Engineering

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CORELLIUM 2022-Present

# Principal Data Engineer - Delrey Beach, FL

Leading company wide analytics for an IOS/Device startup. Using the latest in AWS, Python, Snowflake, Prefect, FiveTran, Segment, Google Analytics, Tableau and other best of breed technologies.

- Working with Executives to create dashboards and analytics for internal metrics.
- Creating Python ETL code to move large amounts of data into Snowflake.
- Developed a process for data sharing with partner companies.

JUPITER INTELLIGENCE 2021-2022

# Sr. Software Engineer – San Mateo, CA / Boulder, CO

Developed a global climate platform for a series C \$54 million+ start-up at the intersection of data science, data engineering and software engineering. Leveraging the latest in AWS, Snowflake and data science to predict perils and climate change.

- Worked directly with software engineering, data science and product owners on delivering a GIS cloud platform.
- Developed a data warehouse for Geospatial data on Snowflake for petabytes of data.
- Created Python ETL code to move large amounts of data into Snowflake.

PANASONIC 2018 – 2021

## Lead Data Scientist - Denver, CO

Led the data science effort on a \$100 million+ multi-year project on one of the largest V2X - connected vehicles projects across the US. Created models to add intelligence to the Cirrus platform. Leveraged the latest technologies in AWS such as Kinesis Analytics, Machine Learning, Athena, Glue, Lambda, QuickSight, Snowflake, and Tableau.

- Co-developed data science models through cross-company collaboration.
- Wrote python code for data pipelines, web scraping, and modeling for GIS, segmentation, telematics data.

DATA ANALYTICS 2012 – 2018

# Principal Consultant - Denver, CO

Led and delivered entire data analytic environments from end to end - leading ETL requirements, data modeling, implementation, and project management on small to large projects. Conducted business analysis, logical and physical database design, database optimization, load strategy design, implement security and change management.

- London Trust Media (Technology) Developed a multi-million dollar Amazon S3 Data Lake with server less technologies using Athena for schema on read, and QuickSight for visualization. Developed customized data pipeline with Python, Lambda, Cloud Watch and EC2 for automated reporting, working directly with the US and Brazil teams.
- Coalfire (Security)— Implemented best in class cloud data warehouse from end-to-end using AWS cloud services, Informatica Cloud for data pipelines, Tableau for visualization, and Python for log files.
- **Zimmer Biomet (Healthcare)** Data Integration project for \$13.4 Billion merger of Zimmer Biomet, one of the largest Biomedical companies in the Spine division using SAP and SAP Data Services for ETL. Worked with multiple teams across the globe.
- Pinnacle (Agriculture) Developed an SSIS XML based regulatory system that saved the company thousands of dollars and reduced auditing.
- Kaiser Permanente (Healthcare) Led the Business Objects 4.1 implementation in the Colorado region for a reporting system valued at over \$50M dollars. The implementation included a large node clustered environment of 20 servers that provided fail over and load balancing support for 1200+ Deski and 1800+ Webi reports with 400+ users and 100s of bursed reports. The ETL was run on Informatica to load 1 Terabyte of data into a data store from DB2, Teradata, Oracle and SQL server.

ANTHONY RODEZ

2 | P a g e

• Comcast/NBC-NETO (Technology/Media)- Developed Big Data/predictive analytic reporting using Pentaho ETL and Cognos 10.2 and SSAS cubes saving Comcast support over \$5M monthly due to reduction of truck roles and proper use of LOQs (Line of Questioning) in an SCRUM/Agile team environment. The data was sourced from large-scale IVR systems using Pentaho ETL.

QLEARVISTA 2008 - 2012

Senior Consultant - Denver, CO

Managed initiatives along with the executive team on progress and implementation methodology on multi-million dollar projects. Designed data warehouses using Kimball methodology and customized reports using best practices. Agrium Advanced Technologies (Agriculture) - Implemented Sales dashboards and data warehouse internationally in BO XI3.1 with an implementation cost of over \$5M. The implementation was a data warehouse built on SQL Server 2008 using SSIS and Kimball methodology. The development included Sales, Finance, Operations, Marketing, Human Resources, Inventory, IT and International Operations.

- CoBank (Banking) Developed and migrated over 200 reports in Cognos 8.4 in an Immon Data warehouse for a banking entity.
- Vail Resorts (Resort) Developed a new data warehouse using Kimball Methodology, SSIS and SQL Server 2008 for the Marketing and Sales department to understand customer metrics that would increase marketing campaigns by \$2M.
- WJ Bradley (Banking) Implemented the Microsoft BI Stack using MS SQL Server suite of tools for a \$20M startup mortgage firm. The data was sourced from a Postgres database using SSIS and then transformed into a SQL Server 2008 database.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Cloud: Snowflake, AWS, GCP, AZURE, Databricks

**Data Science:** Apache Spark, Azure Machine Learning, Jupyter Notebooks, RStudio, AWS ML **Python Libraries:** Beautiful Soup, PETL, Matplotlib, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Seaborn, Scikit Learn

**Programming:** SQL, Python, R programming, JAVA, C, C#, PowerShell, PySpark

BI Tools: SAP - SAP BW, Business Objects, Webi & Deski, Designer, Excelsius, BO Explorer, Lumira,

Crystal Reports, BO Mobile / **IBM** - Cognos 10.2 Report Studio, Query Studio, Framework manager, Transformer, Powerplay, Analysis Studio, Event studio, DMR, Brio Query / Sisense /

Microsoft - SSRS, SSMS, SSAS, SSIS / Oracle - Discoverer / Virtualization - Denodo

Visualization: Kepler, Tableau, Apache Superset

ETL Tools: Prefect, Informatica – Cloud & Power Center 8.6, SAP Data Services, MS SSIS, Pentaho, Prefect

**Databases:** AWS Redshift, DynamoDB, Oracle, SOL Server, Postgres, Teradata, DB2, MS Access

Containers: Docker, AWS ECR

**APIs:** REST, WSDL, HTTP, Postman, Python Requests

**ERP Systems:** SAP, Oracle, PeopleSoft, J.D. Edwards, IBM systems, Netsuite–OpenAir

Web: Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Dynamic HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Wordpress, Flask PM Tools: Atlassian - JIRA, Confluence, Trello, Rally, MS Project, Agile / SCRUM, SmartSheets

**Version Control:** Github, Gitlab, Subversion **Documentation Tools:** Lucidehart, Miro, MS Visio

#### **EDUCATION**

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Professional Education 2021-2024

Focus: Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence

University of Colorado Denver - M.B.A. Information Systems 2003

Focus: IS Management, Databases, Programming

University of Colorado Denver - M.S. Finance

Focus: Security Analysis, Economics, Statistics

University of Colorado Boulder - B.A. International Business / Pre Med 1999

Focus: Sciences, International business, Languages

#### **LANGUAGES**

**German** - Volkshochschule Offenburg, Germany – Proficiency: B2 / **Spanish** - Universidad de Alicante, Spain – Proficiency: C1 /

French - Alliance Française Denver, CO - Proficiency: A1

### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

**Graph Algorithms and Machine Learning** – MIT - August 2022

Machine Learning for Big Data and Text Processing: Advanced – MIT - June 2021

Machine Learning for Big Data and Text Processing: Foundations – MIT - January 2021

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthonyrodez/